<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ADK on A Square Dozen</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/adk/</link><description>Recent content in ADK on A Square Dozen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 16:11:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/adk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Debugging SCCM/ConfigMgr Task Sequences on the Fly</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/10/03/debugging-sccm-configmgr-task-sequences-on-the-fly/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 16:11:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/10/03/debugging-sccm-configmgr-task-sequences-on-the-fly/</guid><description>If you have worked with SCCM/ConfigMgr Task Sequences for any length of time, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely needed to debug them. Many times, you need to check the value of a Task Sequence variable. The generally accepted approach is to add a Run Command Line step to your Task Sequence and run ServiceUI.exe like this:
ServiceUI.exe -process:TSProgressUI.exe cmd.exe
This approach is great if you planned ahead and you are in a test Task Sequence.</description></item><item><title>Adding Dynamic Updates to Windows 10 In-Place Upgrade Media During Offline Servicing</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/08/20/adding-dynamic-updates-to-windows-10-in-place-upgrade-media-during-offline-servicing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 06:14:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/08/20/adding-dynamic-updates-to-windows-10-in-place-upgrade-media-during-offline-servicing/</guid><description>For the past few months, there has been a community-wide push to determine the optimal approach for Offline Servicing Windows 10 media and to get Microsoft to take on more of this burden so we can get on with other tasks instead of dealing with servicing every month. Ultimately, Microsoft needs a better process for updating media each month, but until they do, all we can do is what we do best, Socially Engineer solutions.</description></item><item><title>Clearing Local Group Policies during an Windows 7 to 10 In-Place Upgrade Task Sequence</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/07/16/clearing-local-group-policies-during-an-windows-7-to-10-in-place-upgrade-task-sequence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 07:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/07/16/clearing-local-group-policies-during-an-windows-7-to-10-in-place-upgrade-task-sequence/</guid><description>Our Windows 7 Reference Image was originally built in 2011. At the time, we had some consultants in helping us migrate from Windows XP to Windows 7. At the time, the consultant who was building the image edited the Local Group Polices on the Windows 7 machine prior to capturing it. Since then, we&amp;rsquo;ve continued to service the WIM and use it as our production image. Some years later, we were trying to change our Windows Update settings and found these nice Local Group Policies just sitting there screwing everything up!</description></item><item><title>WinPE Image fails to load on HP Proliant Gen9 servers using ADK 1709</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/01/27/winpe-image-fails-load-hp-proliant-gen9-servers-using-adk-1709/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 02:15:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/01/27/winpe-image-fails-load-hp-proliant-gen9-servers-using-adk-1709/</guid><description>We have several generations of HP ProLiant servers in our environment. We recently upgraded SCCM to 1710 then applied ADK 1709. We have been imaging these servers using the ADK 1703 Boot Image without issue. After upgrading to ADK 1709 and creating new boot images, we are unable to boot to into WinPE on any of our Gen9 servers. After doing the standard diagnostics (testing old, testing new, updating drivers, updating firmware, etc) we found that these servers would still freeze after downloading the boot WIM and get stuck on this screen:</description></item></channel></rss>