<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Intune on A Square Dozen</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/intune/</link><description>Recent content in Intune on A Square Dozen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 07:31:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/intune/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Remove Windows 10 In-Box Apps with ConfigMgr or Intune and the Microsoft Store for Business</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/08/06/remove-windows-10-in-box-apps-with-configmgr-or-intune-and-the-microsoft-store-for-business/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 07:31:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/08/06/remove-windows-10-in-box-apps-with-configmgr-or-intune-and-the-microsoft-store-for-business/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been managing Windows 10 for very long, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely implemented a script or other method to remove some of the In-Box apps that come with Windows 10. We have been using a customized version of a script that Michael Niehaus published in 2015. It uses PowerShell and an XML file with a list of apps to be removed. I have integrated it into my Windows 10 offline servicing script that I use to apply updates to my image each month.</description></item><item><title>ConfigMgr AdminService and WMI Methods – A match made in the cloud (1910)</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/11/29/configmgr-adminservice-and-wmi-methods-a-match-made-in-the-cloud-1910/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 22:12:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/11/29/configmgr-adminservice-and-wmi-methods-a-match-made-in-the-cloud-1910/</guid><description>This post applies to Microsoft Endpoint Configuration Manager 1910 Current Branch
At Microsoft Ignite 2019 Brad Anderson demoed a few things in his sessions, later covered more in depth in other sessions, that highlighted some new features to allow you to leverage the cloud console to manage ConfigMgr-only devices. As I watched these sessions, I realized that they were using the ConfigMgr Administration Service to do integrate into the cloud.</description></item><item><title>Windows 10 Feature Updates – Using Setupconfig.ini to Manage Feature Updates in the Enterprise</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/08/25/windows-10-feature-updates-using-setupconfig-ini-to-manage-feature-updates-in-the-enterprise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:24:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/08/25/windows-10-feature-updates-using-setupconfig-ini-to-manage-feature-updates-in-the-enterprise/</guid><description>This is the next installment in my Windows 10 Feature Updates series.
Setupconfig.ini Setupconfig.ini is a file that can be used to pass command line arguments to the Windows Setup engine during a Windows installation. When Setupconfig.ini is specified in the command line (/ConfigFile &amp;lt;path to Setupconfig.ini&amp;gt;) or exists in the default location (%systemdrive%\Users\Default\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\WSUS\Setupconfig.ini), any arguments in it will take precedence over arguments specified in the commandline. If you use this file, ensure that you aren&amp;rsquo;t counteracting commandline args that you may be using with other deployment methods such as Task Sequences (Task Sequences simply generate a command line based on which options you select).</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting Win32 App Installs in Intune</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/08/21/troubleshooting-win32-app-installs-in-intune/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 06:32:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/08/21/troubleshooting-win32-app-installs-in-intune/</guid><description>As you may know, Steven Hosking and I recently started a YouTube channel called Intune.Training where we are walking through how to get started with Microsoft Intune each week. As we were recording our latest episode (coming soon) on Win32 applications, the demo failed when we attempted to install the application we had just built in Intune. We didn&amp;rsquo;t have time in the video to go through troubleshooting the issue, but I later determined the issue.</description></item><item><title>How to Use Profiles in Microsoft’s Chromium Edge for Managing Multiple Accounts in Azure, Teams and More</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/08/15/how-to-use-profiles-in-microsofts-chromium-edge-for-managing-multiple-accounts-in-azure-teams-and-more/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 06:01:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/08/15/how-to-use-profiles-in-microsofts-chromium-edge-for-managing-multiple-accounts-in-azure-teams-and-more/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never been a fan of alternate web browsers (Chrome, Firefox, etc), not because I don&amp;rsquo;t believe they may have better features than Internet Explorer or Edge, but because I live in the End User Computing space and find it easier to support users if I use the same browsers that they do. Even at home, I keep it simple and just use Edge or IE to help reduce my frustration of having different features depending on where I may be logged in each day.</description></item><item><title>ConfigMgr 1906 Technical Preview – Testing CMPivot over CMG using AdminService</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/06/18/configmgr-1906-technical-preview-testing-cmpivot-over-cmg-using-adminservice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 02:50:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/06/18/configmgr-1906-technical-preview-testing-cmpivot-over-cmg-using-adminservice/</guid><description>ConfigMgr 1906 Technical Preview was released last week and I immediately upgraded one of my tech preview labs I have running in Hyper-V on my laptop. As you may know, I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of the new AdminService functionality which will allow you to interact with the SMS Provider over HTTPS. With each release, it has had more features added. With Tech preview 1906, I noticed that you can run CMPivot using the AdminService.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Microsoft Store for Business Apps from ConfigMgr</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/05/12/deploying-microsoft-store-for-business-apps-from-configmgr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 04:28:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/05/12/deploying-microsoft-store-for-business-apps-from-configmgr/</guid><description>In a previous post I described how to deploy applications to users using Active Directory (AD) security groups as direct members of ConfigMgr collections. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll go over how to integrate the Microsoft Store for Business into your ConfigMgr console and review the various ways to deploy these apps from ConfigMgr. While Microsoft has done great job documenting individual parts of this process, I had to jump all over to find everything.</description></item></channel></rss>