<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MMSMOA on A Square Dozen</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/mmsmoa/</link><description>Recent content in MMSMOA on A Square Dozen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 18:52:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/mmsmoa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Troubleshooting ConfigMgr Enhanced HTTP and Azure Directory Group Sync</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/08/07/troubleshooting-configmgr-enhanced-http-and-azure-directory-group-sync/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 18:52:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/08/07/troubleshooting-configmgr-enhanced-http-and-azure-directory-group-sync/</guid><description>Today I got to help my buddy Adam Juelich with getting ConfigMgr Azure Directory Group Sync working. It&amp;rsquo;s an awesome new feature that allows you to sync ConfigMgr collection memberships to your Azure tenant. Adam had followed all of the steps and ensured that prerequisites were all configured properly but sync would never work.
Over a Teams meeting we double checked everything and walked through Ronny Dejong&amp;rsquo;s (He covers pretty much all of troubleshooting steps needed for this!</description></item><item><title>Gather No More – Using Dynamic Task Sequence Variables in ConfigMgr</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/02/20/gather-no-more-using-dynamic-task-sequence-variables-in-configmgr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 02:15:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/02/20/gather-no-more-using-dynamic-task-sequence-variables-in-configmgr/</guid><description>Update 09/14/2020 - You can download the Gather Light Task Sequence from the Community Hub now! https://communityhub.microsoft.com/item/7812
Update 02/21/2020 - I added a new section with a Gather Task Sequence. Check out the DIY Gather in the Task Sequence section below. It even has a GIF (unlike Software Center!)
If you&amp;rsquo;ve used the Microsoft Deployment ToolKit (MDT) or ConfigMgr or have ever heard of &amp;lsquo;Johan and Mikael&amp;rsquo;, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely used or at least heard/read about using MDT and the Gather script that&amp;rsquo;s included with it as part of your Task Sequences.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Microsoft Store for Business Apps from ConfigMgr</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/05/12/deploying-microsoft-store-for-business-apps-from-configmgr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 04:28:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/05/12/deploying-microsoft-store-for-business-apps-from-configmgr/</guid><description>In a previous post I described how to deploy applications to users using Active Directory (AD) security groups as direct members of ConfigMgr collections. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll go over how to integrate the Microsoft Store for Business into your ConfigMgr console and review the various ways to deploy these apps from ConfigMgr. While Microsoft has done great job documenting individual parts of this process, I had to jump all over to find everything.</description></item></channel></rss>