<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CMPivot on A Square Dozen</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/cmpivot/</link><description>Recent content in CMPivot on A Square Dozen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/cmpivot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using the ConfigMgr AdminService to Retrieve BitLocker Recovery Keys and Triggering Key Rotation</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2021/11/17/using-the-configmgr-adminservice-to-retrieve-bitlocker-recovery-keys-and-triggering-key-rotation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2021/11/17/using-the-configmgr-adminservice-to-retrieve-bitlocker-recovery-keys-and-triggering-key-rotation/</guid><description>The Key to Success is Knowledge Recently Garth Jones accused me of knowing something that I knew nothing about and I was very offended by that. So much so, that when Bryan Dam came to me demanding to know the keys to BitLocker keys in ConfigMgr, I decided I should figure it out. So I did. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I know now:
Keying in on the Issue When trying to automate processes around ConfigMgr, there are Ways to do things then there are Supported Ways to do things.</description></item><item><title>CMPivot Reference</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2021/11/14/cmpivot_reference/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2021/11/14/cmpivot_reference/</guid><description>The following examples were compiled from the CMPivot Home screen examples and the PowerShell equivalent commands were extracted from the CMPivot PowerShell script that is copied down locally to C:\Windows\CCM\ScriptStore. The goal is the provide a way to understand what each command is actually doing when you run it.
Interpreting this Reference Query Type
WMI - The command run locally on the client is querying WMI. Any entity not listed here but available in CMPivot uses the same WMI Class that ConfigMgr Client Hardware Inventory uses.</description></item><item><title>Demystifying Windows 10 Feature Update Blocks</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/07/26/demystifying-windows-10-feature-update-blocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 04:00:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/07/26/demystifying-windows-10-feature-update-blocks/</guid><description>Disclaimer - if you manually bypass Feature Update blocks, you risk causing issues with your device. The blocks exist for a reason and should be respected. This information is provided for educational purposes only. Proceed with caution.
Windows 10 Feature Updates are released twice per year. For each release, Microsoft has the ability to block the update from being installed or even showing up in Widows Update for applications/drivers/devices that have known compatibility issues.</description></item><item><title>ConfigMgr 1906 Technical Preview – Testing CMPivot over CMG using AdminService</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/06/18/configmgr-1906-technical-preview-testing-cmpivot-over-cmg-using-adminservice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 02:50:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/06/18/configmgr-1906-technical-preview-testing-cmpivot-over-cmg-using-adminservice/</guid><description>ConfigMgr 1906 Technical Preview was released last week and I immediately upgraded one of my tech preview labs I have running in Hyper-V on my laptop. As you may know, I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of the new AdminService functionality which will allow you to interact with the SMS Provider over HTTPS. With each release, it has had more features added. With Tech preview 1906, I noticed that you can run CMPivot using the AdminService.</description></item></channel></rss>