<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Applications on A Square Dozen</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/applications/</link><description>Recent content in Applications on A Square Dozen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 07:31:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/applications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Remove Windows 10 In-Box Apps with ConfigMgr or Intune and the Microsoft Store for Business</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/08/06/remove-windows-10-in-box-apps-with-configmgr-or-intune-and-the-microsoft-store-for-business/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 07:31:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/08/06/remove-windows-10-in-box-apps-with-configmgr-or-intune-and-the-microsoft-store-for-business/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been managing Windows 10 for very long, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely implemented a script or other method to remove some of the In-Box apps that come with Windows 10. We have been using a customized version of a script that Michael Niehaus published in 2015. It uses PowerShell and an XML file with a list of apps to be removed. I have integrated it into my Windows 10 offline servicing script that I use to apply updates to my image each month.</description></item><item><title>Debugging “Failed to compile rule” client errors after SCCM Application Catalog Role Removal</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/07/10/debugging-failed-to-compile-rule-client-errors-after-sccm-application-catalog-role-removal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 07:06:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/07/10/debugging-failed-to-compile-rule-client-errors-after-sccm-application-catalog-role-removal/</guid><description>In my post Removing the Application Catalog Role after Upgrading to ConfigMgr 1806 I mentioned the error Failed to compile rule &amp;quot;{Rule_WRC10000}&amp;quot;: 0x8000ffff and that we were unsure of it&amp;rsquo;s impact on the client. The product group assured us that the error was nothing to worry about and they were right - I have seen no ill effects on my clients, even though I continually see this error whenever the clients process machine policies.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Microsoft Store for Business Apps from ConfigMgr</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/05/12/deploying-microsoft-store-for-business-apps-from-configmgr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 04:28:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/05/12/deploying-microsoft-store-for-business-apps-from-configmgr/</guid><description>In a previous post I described how to deploy applications to users using Active Directory (AD) security groups as direct members of ConfigMgr collections. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll go over how to integrate the Microsoft Store for Business into your ConfigMgr console and review the various ways to deploy these apps from ConfigMgr. While Microsoft has done great job documenting individual parts of this process, I had to jump all over to find everything.</description></item></channel></rss>