<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SQL on A Square Dozen</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/sql/</link><description>Recent content in SQL on A Square Dozen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 21:53:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to find Settings Preventing Application Deletion in ConfigMgr</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2021/01/12/how-to-find-settings-preventing-application-deletion-in-configmgr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 21:53:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2021/01/12/how-to-find-settings-preventing-application-deletion-in-configmgr/</guid><description>Today my co-worker was attempting to delete an old application and got blocked with the following message message and I wanted to document it for future reference.
Configuration Manager cannot delete this application because other applications or task sequences reference it or it is configured as a deployment. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 Configuration Manager cannot delete this application because other applications or task sequences reference it or it is configured as a deployment.</description></item><item><title>Analyze SetupDiag errors for Feature Updates in ConfigMgr 2008 Technical Preview</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/08/11/analyze-setupdiag-errors-for-feature-updates-in-configmgr-2008-technical-preview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 04:03:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/08/11/analyze-setupdiag-errors-for-feature-updates-in-configmgr-2008-technical-preview/</guid><description>As soon as I read the release notes for ConfigMgr 2008 Technical Preview I knew I would be doing some digging. This release introduced the first iteration of a feature that will hopefully help make Windows 10 Feature Update servicing a little easier to manage. Listed as Analyze SetupDiag errors for feature updates this feature has been added to the Windows 10 Servicing dashboard. When I initially read the release notes and looked at the included graph, I was disappointed.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting ConfigMgr Enhanced HTTP and Azure Directory Group Sync</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/08/07/troubleshooting-configmgr-enhanced-http-and-azure-directory-group-sync/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 18:52:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/08/07/troubleshooting-configmgr-enhanced-http-and-azure-directory-group-sync/</guid><description>Today I got to help my buddy Adam Juelich with getting ConfigMgr Azure Directory Group Sync working. It&amp;rsquo;s an awesome new feature that allows you to sync ConfigMgr collection memberships to your Azure tenant. Adam had followed all of the steps and ensured that prerequisites were all configured properly but sync would never work.
Over a Teams meeting we double checked everything and walked through Ronny Dejong&amp;rsquo;s (He covers pretty much all of troubleshooting steps needed for this!</description></item><item><title>How to Identify Repeated SCCM Client Inventory Failures Using SQL</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/07/17/how-to-identify-repeated-sccm-client-inventory-failures-using/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 22:49:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/07/17/how-to-identify-repeated-sccm-client-inventory-failures-using/</guid><description>For the past few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been chasing some issues in my production ConfigMgr environment related to Windows 7 to Windows 10 upgrades and Windows 10 Feature Updates and SCCM Hardware Inventory. During that process, I found that several of my clients had successfully been upgraded, but were still reporting the old OS version in the ConfigMgr console. My search led to several root causes which I&amp;rsquo;m still working through, but the solution in most cases was to force a Full Hardware Inventory on the client or fully uninstall, clean and reinstall the client - I also won&amp;rsquo;t go into those steps here.</description></item><item><title>Find Columns and Object Definitions in SQL Server</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/03/11/find-columns-and-object-definitions-in-sql-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 07:09:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/03/11/find-columns-and-object-definitions-in-sql-server/</guid><description>A few years ago, I needed to find a query that I had written in a SQL Stored Procedure but after clicking through several of them and striking out, I decided that there had to be a better way. I ended up writing a simple Stored Procedure with a single search parameter that would return a stored procedure definition and excerpt from it. I like it so much that I&amp;rsquo;ve added it to every database I&amp;rsquo;ve managed since then.</description></item></channel></rss>