<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dynamic Updates on A Square Dozen</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/dynamic-updates/</link><description>Recent content in Dynamic Updates on A Square Dozen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 04:00:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/dynamic-updates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Demystifying Windows 10 Feature Update Blocks</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/07/26/demystifying-windows-10-feature-update-blocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 04:00:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/07/26/demystifying-windows-10-feature-update-blocks/</guid><description>Disclaimer - if you manually bypass Feature Update blocks, you risk causing issues with your device. The blocks exist for a reason and should be respected. This information is provided for educational purposes only. Proceed with caution.
Windows 10 Feature Updates are released twice per year. For each release, Microsoft has the ability to block the update from being installed or even showing up in Widows Update for applications/drivers/devices that have known compatibility issues.</description></item><item><title>Windows 10 Feature Updates – The Challenge of Servicing in the Enterprise</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/10/05/windows-10-feature-updates-the-challenge-of-servicing-in-the-enterprise/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 15:09:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/10/05/windows-10-feature-updates-the-challenge-of-servicing-in-the-enterprise/</guid><description>I hope I never have to build another Task Sequence again. Seriously. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t that be nice? I know that&amp;rsquo;s not truly feasible, but can&amp;rsquo;t a guy dream? It&amp;rsquo;s not that I dislike Task Sequences, it&amp;rsquo;s just that I strongly believe that Modern Desktop Management (AutoPilot/Device Reset/Feature Update servicing/etc.) is going to continue to improve and we should continue to attempt to adopt these tools with as much effort as we spend on customizing Task Sequences.</description></item><item><title>Windows 10 Feature Updates – Using Custom Action Scripts</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/08/25/windows-10-feature-updates-using-custom-action-scripts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 05:28:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/08/25/windows-10-feature-updates-using-custom-action-scripts/</guid><description>This is the next installment in my Windows 10 Feature Updates series.
Custom Actions Beginning in Windows 10 1803, custom actions were introduced and represent what Suma SaganeGowda referred to as a &amp;lsquo;poor man&amp;rsquo;s implementation of Task Sequences&amp;rsquo; at Ignite 2018 in session BRK3027. Windows setup will check for the existence of these special folders and scripts and use them as part of the Feature Update process. They allow you to run scripts at various stages in the Feature Update process as well as specify reflected driver paths just as you can in Setupconfig.</description></item><item><title>Windows 10 Feature Updates – Using Setupconfig.ini to Manage Feature Updates in the Enterprise</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/08/25/windows-10-feature-updates-using-setupconfig-ini-to-manage-feature-updates-in-the-enterprise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:24:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/08/25/windows-10-feature-updates-using-setupconfig-ini-to-manage-feature-updates-in-the-enterprise/</guid><description>This is the next installment in my Windows 10 Feature Updates series.
Setupconfig.ini Setupconfig.ini is a file that can be used to pass command line arguments to the Windows Setup engine during a Windows installation. When Setupconfig.ini is specified in the command line (/ConfigFile &amp;lt;path to Setupconfig.ini&amp;gt;) or exists in the default location (%systemdrive%\Users\Default\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\WSUS\Setupconfig.ini), any arguments in it will take precedence over arguments specified in the commandline. If you use this file, ensure that you aren&amp;rsquo;t counteracting commandline args that you may be using with other deployment methods such as Task Sequences (Task Sequences simply generate a command line based on which options you select).</description></item><item><title>Adding Dynamic Updates to Windows 10 In-Place Upgrade Media During Offline Servicing</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/08/20/adding-dynamic-updates-to-windows-10-in-place-upgrade-media-during-offline-servicing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 06:14:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/08/20/adding-dynamic-updates-to-windows-10-in-place-upgrade-media-during-offline-servicing/</guid><description>For the past few months, there has been a community-wide push to determine the optimal approach for Offline Servicing Windows 10 media and to get Microsoft to take on more of this burden so we can get on with other tasks instead of dealing with servicing every month. Ultimately, Microsoft needs a better process for updating media each month, but until they do, all we can do is what we do best, Socially Engineer solutions.</description></item></channel></rss>