<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AdminService on A Square Dozen</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/tags/adminservice/</link><description>Recent content in AdminService on A Square Dozen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 22:12:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.asquaredozen.com/tags/adminservice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ConfigMgr AdminService and WMI Methods – A match made in the cloud (1910)</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/11/29/configmgr-adminservice-and-wmi-methods-a-match-made-in-the-cloud-1910/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 22:12:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/11/29/configmgr-adminservice-and-wmi-methods-a-match-made-in-the-cloud-1910/</guid><description>This post applies to Microsoft Endpoint Configuration Manager 1910 Current Branch
At Microsoft Ignite 2019 Brad Anderson demoed a few things in his sessions, later covered more in depth in other sessions, that highlighted some new features to allow you to leverage the cloud console to manage ConfigMgr-only devices. As I watched these sessions, I realized that they were using the ConfigMgr Administration Service to do integrate into the cloud.</description></item><item><title>ConfigMgr 1906 Technical Preview – Testing CMPivot over CMG using AdminService</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/06/18/configmgr-1906-technical-preview-testing-cmpivot-over-cmg-using-adminservice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 02:50:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/06/18/configmgr-1906-technical-preview-testing-cmpivot-over-cmg-using-adminservice/</guid><description>ConfigMgr 1906 Technical Preview was released last week and I immediately upgraded one of my tech preview labs I have running in Hyper-V on my laptop. As you may know, I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of the new AdminService functionality which will allow you to interact with the SMS Provider over HTTPS. With each release, it has had more features added. With Tech preview 1906, I noticed that you can run CMPivot using the AdminService.</description></item></channel></rss>