<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>1906 on A Square Dozen</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/1906/</link><description>Recent content in 1906 on A Square Dozen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 05:57:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/1906/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Windows 10 Feature Updates – Leveraging SetupDiag for Better Reporting</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/08/22/windows-10-feature-updates-leveraging-setupdiag-for-better-reporting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 05:57:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/08/22/windows-10-feature-updates-leveraging-setupdiag-for-better-reporting/</guid><description>This is the first post of my Windows 10 Feature Updates series, probably totally out of sequence, but I just need to start getting the pieces written and published. So here goes.
What is SetupDiag If you have worked with Windows 10 Operating System Deployments for any amount of time, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely had failures and encountered cryptic messages that you needed to triage. Hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ve come across SetupDiag. For the uninitiated, SetupDiag is a fancy little tool from Microsoft that you can run against the Windows installation logs (Panther Logs) either directly on a client or against an offline copy of the Panther logs from another client.</description></item><item><title>ConfigMgr 1906 Technical Preview – Testing CMPivot over CMG using AdminService</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/06/18/configmgr-1906-technical-preview-testing-cmpivot-over-cmg-using-adminservice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 02:50:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/06/18/configmgr-1906-technical-preview-testing-cmpivot-over-cmg-using-adminservice/</guid><description>ConfigMgr 1906 Technical Preview was released last week and I immediately upgraded one of my tech preview labs I have running in Hyper-V on my laptop. As you may know, I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of the new AdminService functionality which will allow you to interact with the SMS Provider over HTTPS. With each release, it has had more features added. With Tech preview 1906, I noticed that you can run CMPivot using the AdminService.</description></item></channel></rss>