<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>1810 on A Square Dozen</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/1810/</link><description>Recent content in 1810 on A Square Dozen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 07:06:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/1810/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Debugging “Failed to compile rule” client errors after SCCM Application Catalog Role Removal</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/07/10/debugging-failed-to-compile-rule-client-errors-after-sccm-application-catalog-role-removal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 07:06:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/07/10/debugging-failed-to-compile-rule-client-errors-after-sccm-application-catalog-role-removal/</guid><description>In my post Removing the Application Catalog Role after Upgrading to ConfigMgr 1806 I mentioned the error Failed to compile rule &amp;quot;{Rule_WRC10000}&amp;quot;: 0x8000ffff and that we were unsure of it&amp;rsquo;s impact on the client. The product group assured us that the error was nothing to worry about and they were right - I have seen no ill effects on my clients, even though I continually see this error whenever the clients process machine policies.</description></item><item><title>The Microsoft Endpoint Configuration Manager Administration Service Guide</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/02/12/the-system-center-configuration-manager-adminservice-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 07:45:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/02/12/the-system-center-configuration-manager-adminservice-guide/</guid><description>This post is dedicated to the System Center Configuration Manger (SCCM/ConfigMgr) Administration Service (AdminService for short). Please check back here for helpful links and to blog posts, documentation and examples for using the AdminService. Please note, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what the name was officially when I first started, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to keep posting new info about it, so sorry if it&amp;rsquo;s disjointed.
Update: 11/3/2109 - I am updating this post to show information for the the latest ConfigMgr Current Branch release.</description></item><item><title>Building a Better Task Sequence</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/11/29/building-a-better-task-sequence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 06:41:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/11/29/building-a-better-task-sequence/</guid><description>Be sure to check out the sequel to this post Building an Even Better Task Sequence.
I&amp;rsquo;ve had this post in the queue for a while now and have been working on a script to help with some of this, but with the release of System Center Configuration Manager 1810 I don&amp;rsquo;t have to hack something together anymore! One of the best new features which allows us to capture the name of the last action using the new variable _SMSTSLastActionName.</description></item><item><title>The ConfigMgr AdminService</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/10/23/the-configmgr-adminservice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 06:53:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/10/23/the-configmgr-adminservice/</guid><description>Update 12/04/2018: Check out the latest info on the SMS Provider API.
I posted last week about the OData connector that is included in ConfigMgr Technical Preview 1810. I did some more digging this past weekend and made a few more discoveries. Additionally, I ran into some issues during testing and was able to get in touch with some of the team working on the new AdminService and they gave me some great insight on my findings.</description></item><item><title>The ConfigMgr OData Web Service – V2</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/10/14/the-configmgr-odata-web-service-v2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 03:41:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/10/14/the-configmgr-odata-web-service-v2/</guid><description>I went to Microsoft Ignite 2018 for the first time this year. During the week, I got to chat with lots of folks, including some of the SCCM/ConfigMgr product group. Mark Silvey was kind enough to chat with me about plans for the OData connector that was first introduced in ConfigMgr 1612 Technical Preview. When it was first released it was called CMRestProvider and it had to be enabled in the console (you can read more about this initial implementation here).</description></item></channel></rss>