<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>COVID-19 on A Square Dozen</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/covid-19/</link><description>Recent content in COVID-19 on A Square Dozen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 04:49:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/covid-19/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lockdown Diary – Metered Internet Connections and Broken ConfigMgr Clients</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/05/22/lockdown-diary-metered-internet-connections-and-broken-configmgr-clients/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 04:49:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/05/22/lockdown-diary-metered-internet-connections-and-broken-configmgr-clients/</guid><description>Do you know how hard it is to find things when you don&amp;rsquo;t know what to search for??
I&amp;rsquo;m paranoid. We recently upgraded our site to ConfigMgr 2002, first fast ring, then the hotfix. We also installed a Cloud Management Gateway, re-worked our Boundary Groups to handle VPN better, added a second Management Point and generally made a butt-load of changes to our environment to help our remote clients have access to content more easily.</description></item><item><title>Lockdown Diary – My Always On VPN is Schrödinger’s Cat</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/05/12/lockdown-diary-my-always-on-vpn-is-schrodingers-cat/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 04:29:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/05/12/lockdown-diary-my-always-on-vpn-is-schrodingers-cat/</guid><description>When is your Always On VPN not Always On? An Always On VPN client uses a machine certificate to connect to the VPN gateway and connect to the network on startup. This feature is wonderful since it allows VPN clients to process machine group policies and even makes it easy for users with expired passwords to reset their passwords. But how can you verify that the machine channel is connected if you can&amp;rsquo;t see any indicators on the logon screen?</description></item><item><title>LockDown Diary – How I used DJOIN to Build Test Machines over VPN</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/05/05/lockdown-diary-how-i-used-djoin-to-build-test-machines-over-vpn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 05:16:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/05/05/lockdown-diary-how-i-used-djoin-to-build-test-machines-over-vpn/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a few months since I&amp;rsquo;ve sat down to put write something. I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking a break trying to pick up some woodworking skills and spend a bit more time with the family during this COVID-19 lockdown. On March 5, I left work to take a week off for Spring Break and never returned to the office. Today is May 5. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t prepared for being at home and since I don&amp;rsquo;t regularly work from home, I don&amp;rsquo;t have any hardware here other than a normal desk setup.</description></item></channel></rss>