<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>General on A Square Dozen</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/general/</link><description>Recent content in General on A Square Dozen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Consulting</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/consulting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/consulting/</guid><description>I work part time as a consultant with System Center Dudes. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to request my assistance with consulting work, please contact them directly at System Center Dudes. Tell them that Adam sent you :-).</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/contact/</guid><description>If you need to contact me, please send me a DM on Twitter or shoot me an Email.</description></item><item><title>How to find Settings Preventing Application Deletion in ConfigMgr</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2021/01/12/how-to-find-settings-preventing-application-deletion-in-configmgr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 21:53:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2021/01/12/how-to-find-settings-preventing-application-deletion-in-configmgr/</guid><description>Today my co-worker was attempting to delete an old application and got blocked with the following message message and I wanted to document it for future reference.
Configuration Manager cannot delete this application because other applications or task sequences reference it or it is configured as a deployment. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 Configuration Manager cannot delete this application because other applications or task sequences reference it or it is configured as a deployment.</description></item><item><title>Lockdown Diary – My Always On VPN is Schrödinger’s Cat</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/05/12/lockdown-diary-my-always-on-vpn-is-schrodingers-cat/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 04:29:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2020/05/12/lockdown-diary-my-always-on-vpn-is-schrodingers-cat/</guid><description>When is your Always On VPN not Always On? An Always On VPN client uses a machine certificate to connect to the VPN gateway and connect to the network on startup. This feature is wonderful since it allows VPN clients to process machine group policies and even makes it easy for users with expired passwords to reset their passwords. But how can you verify that the machine channel is connected if you can&amp;rsquo;t see any indicators on the logon screen?</description></item><item><title>ConfigMgr AdminService and WMI Methods – A match made in the cloud (1910)</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/11/29/configmgr-adminservice-and-wmi-methods-a-match-made-in-the-cloud-1910/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 22:12:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/11/29/configmgr-adminservice-and-wmi-methods-a-match-made-in-the-cloud-1910/</guid><description>This post applies to Microsoft Endpoint Configuration Manager 1910 Current Branch
At Microsoft Ignite 2019 Brad Anderson demoed a few things in his sessions, later covered more in depth in other sessions, that highlighted some new features to allow you to leverage the cloud console to manage ConfigMgr-only devices. As I watched these sessions, I realized that they were using the ConfigMgr Administration Service to do integrate into the cloud.</description></item><item><title>Find Columns and Object Definitions in SQL Server</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/03/11/find-columns-and-object-definitions-in-sql-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 07:09:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/03/11/find-columns-and-object-definitions-in-sql-server/</guid><description>A few years ago, I needed to find a query that I had written in a SQL Stored Procedure but after clicking through several of them and striking out, I decided that there had to be a better way. I ended up writing a simple Stored Procedure with a single search parameter that would return a stored procedure definition and excerpt from it. I like it so much that I&amp;rsquo;ve added it to every database I&amp;rsquo;ve managed since then.</description></item><item><title>SCCM Collection Evaluation – Troubleshooting Incremental Update Issues</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/02/21/sccm-collection-evaluation-troubleshooting-incremental-update-issues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 07:02:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/02/21/sccm-collection-evaluation-troubleshooting-incremental-update-issues/</guid><description>About a month ago, I wrote a post for System Center Dudes related to the changes to recurring collection schedules in SCCM 1810. In our environment, we removed the default recurring schedules from about 1750 device collections that use Direct membership rules. Up until that point, we had seen some strange collection behaviors, but never at the level that we began to experience them post ConfigMgr 1810. (Let me stop here and say that 1810 didn&amp;rsquo;t break anything.</description></item><item><title>The Microsoft Endpoint Configuration Manager Administration Service Guide</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/02/12/the-system-center-configuration-manager-adminservice-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 07:45:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/02/12/the-system-center-configuration-manager-adminservice-guide/</guid><description>This post is dedicated to the System Center Configuration Manger (SCCM/ConfigMgr) Administration Service (AdminService for short). Please check back here for helpful links and to blog posts, documentation and examples for using the AdminService. Please note, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what the name was officially when I first started, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to keep posting new info about it, so sorry if it&amp;rsquo;s disjointed.
Update: 11/3/2109 - I am updating this post to show information for the the latest ConfigMgr Current Branch release.</description></item><item><title>2018 – Wow, what a ride!</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/01/04/2018-wow-what-a-ride/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 22:19:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/01/04/2018-wow-what-a-ride/</guid><description>I’m not a big New Year’s resolution guy but I do believe that looking back at the previous year as well as setting goals for the coming year helps set up a framework for success. For this post, I’d like to share some personal and professional highlights from 2018.
Personal Family To start, I’m writing this sitting next to my wife Megan as we fly back to Houston after spending 10 amazing days in Thailand celebrating 15 years of marriage.</description></item><item><title>Dessert in the Desert – Highlights of My First MMS Conference (MMSDE)</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/12/07/dessert-in-the-desert-highlights-of-my-first-mms-conference-mmsde/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 03:54:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/12/07/dessert-in-the-desert-highlights-of-my-first-mms-conference-mmsde/</guid><description>At MMS Desert Edition (MMSDE) this week, I got into a (friendly) heated debate over what qualified as BBQ where the other party offered up some very silly arguments related to pulled pork and vinegar sauce. I&amp;rsquo;m a firm believer in meat. Period. Cook it however you want, call it whatever you want. I just want to eat it. This discussion led to some additional &amp;lsquo;South Bashing&amp;rsquo; by this &amp;lsquo;Yankee&amp;rsquo; from North Carolina.</description></item><item><title>Failed to decrypt state encryption key (0x80070057) – Can't get StateEncryptDecryptKey property error in SCCM/ConfigMgr User State Migration Console</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/08/09/failed-to-decrypt-state-encryption-key-0x80070057-cant-get-stateencryptdecryptkey-property-error-in-sccm-configmgr-user-state-migration-console/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 04:14:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/08/09/failed-to-decrypt-state-encryption-key-0x80070057-cant-get-stateencryptdecryptkey-property-error-in-sccm-configmgr-user-state-migration-console/</guid><description>I found this issue today and hope to get some help from the ConfigMgr team on it but figured it was worth writing up the workaround for now.
The Issue While attempting to perform a user state backup on a machine using an SCCM task sequence, we received the error in SMSTS.LOG:
Failed to decrypt state encryption key (0x80070057) Failed to run the action: Request User State Storage. The parameter is incorrect.</description></item><item><title>ConfigMgr Log Sanitizer Powershell Script</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/03/08/configmgr-log-sanitzer-powershell-script/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 19:01:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/03/08/configmgr-log-sanitzer-powershell-script/</guid><description>Do you ever need to email or post ConfigMgr log files or snippets online for blogs or support? I know I do. I wanted to have a way to consistently clean log files quickly, so I wrote a small PowerShell script to help. It&amp;rsquo;s nothing special - the hardest part is figuring out which regular expressions work best for each data type you want to replace. I ended up with 4 regular expressions that work well for the smsts.</description></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/01/16/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 06:26:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/01/16/hello-world/</guid><description>I guess that&amp;rsquo;s how I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to start out.
If you want to know more about me or my site name, please visit the About page before proceeding. I&amp;rsquo;ll wait.
Welcome back! As you can see, I&amp;rsquo;m not an expert, but I have been doing this for a while and just wanted to have a place to call my own where I can post with more than characters on Twitter. I hope that I will be able to add value to the community.</description></item></channel></rss>