<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OData on A Square Dozen</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/odata/</link><description>Recent content in OData on A Square Dozen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 22:12:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/odata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ConfigMgr AdminService and WMI Methods – A match made in the cloud (1910)</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/11/29/configmgr-adminservice-and-wmi-methods-a-match-made-in-the-cloud-1910/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 22:12:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/11/29/configmgr-adminservice-and-wmi-methods-a-match-made-in-the-cloud-1910/</guid><description>This post applies to Microsoft Endpoint Configuration Manager 1910 Current Branch
At Microsoft Ignite 2019 Brad Anderson demoed a few things in his sessions, later covered more in depth in other sessions, that highlighted some new features to allow you to leverage the cloud console to manage ConfigMgr-only devices. As I watched these sessions, I realized that they were using the ConfigMgr Administration Service to do integrate into the cloud.</description></item><item><title>The Microsoft Endpoint Configuration Manager Administration Service Guide</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/02/12/the-system-center-configuration-manager-adminservice-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 07:45:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/02/12/the-system-center-configuration-manager-adminservice-guide/</guid><description>This post is dedicated to the System Center Configuration Manger (SCCM/ConfigMgr) Administration Service (AdminService for short). Please check back here for helpful links and to blog posts, documentation and examples for using the AdminService. Please note, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what the name was officially when I first started, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to keep posting new info about it, so sorry if it&amp;rsquo;s disjointed.
Update: 11/3/2109 - I am updating this post to show information for the the latest ConfigMgr Current Branch release.</description></item><item><title>Updated Information about the AdminService/SMS Provider API in SCCM/ConfigMgr 1810</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/12/04/updated-information-about-the-sms-provider-api-in-sccm-configmgr-1810/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 16:58:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/12/04/updated-information-about-the-sms-provider-api-in-sccm-configmgr-1810/</guid><description>I began testing the ConfigMgr SMS Provider API (or AdminService as it will be called) in the 1810 Technical Preview and wrote 2 posts about it (1) &amp;amp; (2). With the release of the AdminService in Current Branch 1810, a few things have changed and I wanted to provide an update. Additonally, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to chat with the ConfigMgr Product Group at #MMSDE this week and they&amp;rsquo;ve provided some roadmap information about the API and what to expect in the future.</description></item><item><title>The ConfigMgr AdminService</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/10/23/the-configmgr-adminservice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 06:53:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/10/23/the-configmgr-adminservice/</guid><description>Update 12/04/2018: Check out the latest info on the SMS Provider API.
I posted last week about the OData connector that is included in ConfigMgr Technical Preview 1810. I did some more digging this past weekend and made a few more discoveries. Additionally, I ran into some issues during testing and was able to get in touch with some of the team working on the new AdminService and they gave me some great insight on my findings.</description></item><item><title>The ConfigMgr OData Web Service – V2</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/10/14/the-configmgr-odata-web-service-v2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 03:41:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/10/14/the-configmgr-odata-web-service-v2/</guid><description>I went to Microsoft Ignite 2018 for the first time this year. During the week, I got to chat with lots of folks, including some of the SCCM/ConfigMgr product group. Mark Silvey was kind enough to chat with me about plans for the OData connector that was first introduced in ConfigMgr 1612 Technical Preview. When it was first released it was called CMRestProvider and it had to be enabled in the console (you can read more about this initial implementation here).</description></item></channel></rss>