<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Application Catalog on A Square Dozen</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/tags/application-catalog/</link><description>Recent content in Application Catalog on A Square Dozen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 07:06:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.asquaredozen.com/tags/application-catalog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Debugging “Failed to compile rule” client errors after SCCM Application Catalog Role Removal</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/07/10/debugging-failed-to-compile-rule-client-errors-after-sccm-application-catalog-role-removal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 07:06:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/07/10/debugging-failed-to-compile-rule-client-errors-after-sccm-application-catalog-role-removal/</guid><description>In my post Removing the Application Catalog Role after Upgrading to ConfigMgr 1806 I mentioned the error Failed to compile rule &amp;quot;{Rule_WRC10000}&amp;quot;: 0x8000ffff and that we were unsure of it&amp;rsquo;s impact on the client. The product group assured us that the error was nothing to worry about and they were right - I have seen no ill effects on my clients, even though I continually see this error whenever the clients process machine policies.</description></item><item><title>Removing the Application Catalog Role after Upgrading to ConfigMgr 1806</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/11/02/removing-the-application-catalog-role-after-upgrading-to-configmgr-1806/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 21:56:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/11/02/removing-the-application-catalog-role-after-upgrading-to-configmgr-1806/</guid><description>If you have been keeping up with SCCM/ConfigMgr release notes, you will have seen that in 1806, you no longer need to have the Application Catalog Role installed in order to enable User Available applications in Software Center (if you didn&amp;rsquo;t already know, yeah, that was a requirement previously). If you were like me, this was one of your first actions after upgrading to 1806. Unfortunately, there appears to be a bug with removing the role that causes clients to stop seeing User Available software in Software Center.</description></item></channel></rss>