<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Co-Management on A Square Dozen</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/co-management/</link><description>Recent content in Co-Management on A Square Dozen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.asquaredozen.com/categories/co-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using the ConfigMgr AdminService to Retrieve BitLocker Recovery Keys and Triggering Key Rotation</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2021/11/17/using-the-configmgr-adminservice-to-retrieve-bitlocker-recovery-keys-and-triggering-key-rotation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2021/11/17/using-the-configmgr-adminservice-to-retrieve-bitlocker-recovery-keys-and-triggering-key-rotation/</guid><description>The Key to Success is Knowledge Recently Garth Jones accused me of knowing something that I knew nothing about and I was very offended by that. So much so, that when Bryan Dam came to me demanding to know the keys to BitLocker keys in ConfigMgr, I decided I should figure it out. So I did. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I know now:
Keying in on the Issue When trying to automate processes around ConfigMgr, there are Ways to do things then there are Supported Ways to do things.</description></item><item><title>CMPivot Reference</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2021/11/14/cmpivot_reference/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2021/11/14/cmpivot_reference/</guid><description>The following examples were compiled from the CMPivot Home screen examples and the PowerShell equivalent commands were extracted from the CMPivot PowerShell script that is copied down locally to C:\Windows\CCM\ScriptStore. The goal is the provide a way to understand what each command is actually doing when you run it.
Interpreting this Reference Query Type
WMI - The command run locally on the client is querying WMI. Any entity not listed here but available in CMPivot uses the same WMI Class that ConfigMgr Client Hardware Inventory uses.</description></item><item><title>When VDI and ConfigMgr Co-Management Collide</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2021/11/13/when-vdi-and-configmgr-co-management-collide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 04:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2021/11/13/when-vdi-and-configmgr-co-management-collide/</guid><description>Before we begin, here are some notes about persistent and non-persistent VDI that will likely give you nightmares:
Intune doesn&amp;rsquo;t support non-persistent VDI Azure Active Directory only supports Hybrid Azure AD Join for non-persistent VDI ConfigMgr recommends limiting client functionality on non-persistent VDI but there is no mention about the impact of Co-Management on these devices. Whatever you do, don&amp;rsquo;t Hybrid Join then Co-Manage your VDI Master Image or you&amp;rsquo;re in for a bad time!</description></item></channel></rss>