<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ConfigMgr on A Square Dozen</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/tags/configmgr/</link><description>Recent content in ConfigMgr on A Square Dozen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:23:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.asquaredozen.com/tags/configmgr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Convert ConfigMgr Error Codes to Plain Text Messages for Reporting – Part 3</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/11/25/convert-configmgr-error-codes-to-plain-text-messages-for-reporting-part-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:23:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/11/25/convert-configmgr-error-codes-to-plain-text-messages-for-reporting-part-3/</guid><description>I demoed this at MMS Jazz 2019 Tip and Tricks. This is Part 3 of a 3-part series. Part 1covers how to create a PowerShell script to lookup error messages. Part 2 covers creating an Azure Function.
My goal is to use ConfigMgr ErrorCodes in a report in Power BI for easier deployment monitoring. As I mentioned in Part 1, the error text isn&amp;rsquo;t available in the ConfigMgr DB, so I created a PowerShell script to look up the error code.</description></item><item><title>Convert ConfigMgr Error Codes to Plain Text Messages for Reporting – Part 2</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/11/25/convert-configmgr-error-codes-to-plain-text-messages-for-reporting-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 18:56:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/11/25/convert-configmgr-error-codes-to-plain-text-messages-for-reporting-part-2/</guid><description>I demoed this at MMS Jazz 2019 Tip and Tricks. This is Part 2 of a 3-part series. Part 1 covers how to create a PowerShell script to lookup error messages. Part 3 covers how to create a Power BI function to use an Azure Function.
I had heard of Azure Functions and I&amp;rsquo;ve written web API&amp;rsquo;s but I had never put the 2 together until I ran into this dilemma.</description></item><item><title>Convert ConfigMgr Error Codes to Plain Text Messages for Reporting – Part 1</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/11/25/convert-configmgr-error-codes-to-plain-text-messages-for-reporting-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 18:02:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/11/25/convert-configmgr-error-codes-to-plain-text-messages-for-reporting-part-1/</guid><description>I demoed this at MMS Jazz 2019 Tip and Tricks. This is Part 1 of a 3-part series. Part 2 covers creating an Azure Function. Part 3 covers how to create a Power BI function to use an Azure Function.
If you have ever checked the logs in ConfigMgr, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely run across an error code in a format like 0x87D00664 or -2016410012. If use the error lookup feature in CMTrace, you can generally convert the error to plain text.</description></item><item><title>How to Identify Repeated SCCM Client Inventory Failures Using SQL</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/07/17/how-to-identify-repeated-sccm-client-inventory-failures-using/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 22:49:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/07/17/how-to-identify-repeated-sccm-client-inventory-failures-using/</guid><description>For the past few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been chasing some issues in my production ConfigMgr environment related to Windows 7 to Windows 10 upgrades and Windows 10 Feature Updates and SCCM Hardware Inventory. During that process, I found that several of my clients had successfully been upgraded, but were still reporting the old OS version in the ConfigMgr console. My search led to several root causes which I&amp;rsquo;m still working through, but the solution in most cases was to force a Full Hardware Inventory on the client or fully uninstall, clean and reinstall the client - I also won&amp;rsquo;t go into those steps here.</description></item><item><title>ConfigMgr 1906 Technical Preview – Testing CMPivot over CMG using AdminService</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/06/18/configmgr-1906-technical-preview-testing-cmpivot-over-cmg-using-adminservice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 02:50:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2019/06/18/configmgr-1906-technical-preview-testing-cmpivot-over-cmg-using-adminservice/</guid><description>ConfigMgr 1906 Technical Preview was released last week and I immediately upgraded one of my tech preview labs I have running in Hyper-V on my laptop. As you may know, I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of the new AdminService functionality which will allow you to interact with the SMS Provider over HTTPS. With each release, it has had more features added. With Tech preview 1906, I noticed that you can run CMPivot using the AdminService.</description></item><item><title>Dessert in the Desert – Highlights of My First MMS Conference (MMSDE)</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/12/07/dessert-in-the-desert-highlights-of-my-first-mms-conference-mmsde/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 03:54:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/12/07/dessert-in-the-desert-highlights-of-my-first-mms-conference-mmsde/</guid><description>At MMS Desert Edition (MMSDE) this week, I got into a (friendly) heated debate over what qualified as BBQ where the other party offered up some very silly arguments related to pulled pork and vinegar sauce. I&amp;rsquo;m a firm believer in meat. Period. Cook it however you want, call it whatever you want. I just want to eat it. This discussion led to some additional &amp;lsquo;South Bashing&amp;rsquo; by this &amp;lsquo;Yankee&amp;rsquo; from North Carolina.</description></item><item><title>The ConfigMgr OData Web Service – V2</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/10/14/the-configmgr-odata-web-service-v2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 03:41:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/10/14/the-configmgr-odata-web-service-v2/</guid><description>I went to Microsoft Ignite 2018 for the first time this year. During the week, I got to chat with lots of folks, including some of the SCCM/ConfigMgr product group. Mark Silvey was kind enough to chat with me about plans for the OData connector that was first introduced in ConfigMgr 1612 Technical Preview. When it was first released it was called CMRestProvider and it had to be enabled in the console (you can read more about this initial implementation here).</description></item><item><title>Task Sequence Failure "The software could not be found on any servers at this time" Caused by Retired Superseded Applications</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/04/18/task-sequence-failure-the-software-could-not-be-found-on-any-servers-at-this-time-caused-by-retired-superseded-applications/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 21:41:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/04/18/task-sequence-failure-the-software-could-not-be-found-on-any-servers-at-this-time-caused-by-retired-superseded-applications/</guid><description>Today was supposed to be easy. Things were just supposed to work. We had been testing our ConfigMgr Task Sequence for a few weeks and today was cutover day. We had made some backend changes to our Windows 7 Task Sequence to help get ready for our upcoming Windows 10 migration (I know, haven&amp;rsquo;t upgraded yet! Get off my case!). Earlier in the week, we found one last item that needed to be added.</description></item><item><title>WinPE Image fails to load on HP Proliant Gen9 servers using ADK 1709</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/01/27/winpe-image-fails-load-hp-proliant-gen9-servers-using-adk-1709/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 02:15:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/01/27/winpe-image-fails-load-hp-proliant-gen9-servers-using-adk-1709/</guid><description>We have several generations of HP ProLiant servers in our environment. We recently upgraded SCCM to 1710 then applied ADK 1709. We have been imaging these servers using the ADK 1703 Boot Image without issue. After upgrading to ADK 1709 and creating new boot images, we are unable to boot to into WinPE on any of our Gen9 servers. After doing the standard diagnostics (testing old, testing new, updating drivers, updating firmware, etc) we found that these servers would still freeze after downloading the boot WIM and get stuck on this screen:</description></item><item><title>Windows 7 to Windows 10 Fall Creators Update (1709) In-Place Upgrade Fails with error 0xC1900204 (Invalid Sku)</title><link>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/01/16/windows-7-windows-10-fall-creators-update-1709-place-upgrade-fails-error-0xc1900204-invalid-sku/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 19:07:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.asquaredozen.com/2018/01/16/windows-7-windows-10-fall-creators-update-1709-place-upgrade-fails-error-0xc1900204-invalid-sku/</guid><description>We have built an SCCM In-Place upgrade task sequence to migrate our enterprise from Windows 7 Enterprise to Windows 10 Enterprise. We have been using the same basic TS for over a year without issues. With the release of Windows 10 Fall Creators Update (1709), we began having issues upgrading certain devices and were seeing error code 0xC1900204, indicating Invalid SKU.
Windows setup looks at the existing OS, install media and the command line image number to validate that the existing and desired versions are a match and can be upgraded.</description></item></channel></rss>